Christopher Wallace

Product Design Leader

I work with brands like DC Comics, MLB, Mad Men, The Walking Dead, and Breaking Bad to transform the digital product experience for millions of people worldwide. My approach to design is collaborative, reducing technical complexity to simple, delightful experiences for everyday users.

portfolio <u>chriswallace.net</u>

email chriswallace7@pm.me

linkedin linkedin.com/in/chriswallace2

phone +1 972 837 7267

address 6400 Orchard Park Drive, McKinney, TX 75071

Work Experience

Lead Product Designer

Mar 2024 - Oct 2024

<u>Candy Digital</u> — McKinney, TX

Led product design efforts, redesigned website and marketplace, and created a design system. Created an interactive comic book reader app for digital DC Comics and other prototypes. Worked with cross-functional partners to ship new features and improve user experience across our ecosystem of apps.

Chief Design Officer

Apr 2021 - Mar 2024

<u>UltraDAO Studios</u> — McKinney, TX

Founded UltraDAO Studios, created Woodies digital avatars, and led a record crypto donation. Bootstrapped the company to \$2.6m revenue within six months. Released an acclaimed animated short and the first large-scale 3D avatars available on metaverse platforms.

VP Experience Design

Aug 2017 - Sep 2021

10up — McKinney, TX

Expanded design team, led projects for clients like Microsoft and Google, and directed the design team on California DMV's digital transformation. Mentored designers and ensured high-quality client projects.

Principal Creative Director

Dec 2009 - Aug 2017

Lift UX — McKinney, TX

Led design of award-winning, 2x Emmy-nominated digital experiences, including AMC Story Sync (The Walking Dead, Breaking Bad, and Mad Men). Partnered with clients like Frito-Lay and GoDaddy, and ran a WordPress theme business.

Front-End Developer

Aug 2007 - Dec 2009

Enterprise Rent-A-Car — Clayton, MO

Built website tools for booking rentals, ensured smooth design implementation, and maintained website functionality.

Senior E-Commerce Web Designer

May 2006 - Aug 2007

Network Solutions — Belleville, IL

Designed online shops for small businesses, collaborated on branding, and created store templates that matched client needs.

Education

Missouri State University

2004

Graphic Design

Saint Louis Christian College

2002 - 2004

General and Religious Studies

Technical Skills

Figma, design systems, design research, product design, mobile/iOS/Android, design engineering, Rive, Framer, Webflow, Storybook, CSS, Svelte, React, Next.js, Web3, blockchain, responsive design, accessibility

Awards

- Award: Best Environmental Initiative from an NFT project NFT NYC (2022)
- Nominee: Outstanding Creative Achievement in Interactive Media Social TV Experience, Mad Men: The Fan Cut — Emmy Awards (2015)
- Nominee: Outstanding Interactive Program, The Walking Dead Story Sync Emmy Awards (2013)
- Award: Best Second Screen App, The Walking Dead Story Sync Variety Awards (2012)